
// let questions = [
//   {
//     id: 1,
//     question: " Who invented C++?",
//     answer: "Bjarne Stroustrup.",
//     options: [
//       "Dennis Ritchie",
//       "Ken Thompson",
//       "Brian Kernighan",
//       "Bjarne Stroustrup"
//     ]
//   },
//   {
//     id: 2,
//     question: "Which of the following user-defined header file extension used in c++?",
//     answer:"bottom-up",
//     options: [
//       "right-left",
//       "left-right",
//       "bottom-up",
//       "top-down"
//     ]
//   },
//   {
//     id: 3,
//     question:"Which of the following data type is supported in C++ but not in C?",
//     annswer:"bool",
//     options: [
//       "int",
//       "bool",
//       "double",
//       "float"
//     ]
//   },
//   {
//     id: 4,
//     question: "Which of the following user-defined header file extension used in c++?",
//     answer: "h",

//     options: [
//       "hg",
//       "cpp",
//       "h",
//       "hf"
//     ]
//   },
//   {
//     id: 5,
//     question: "Identify the correct syntax for declaring arrays in C++?",
//     answer: "int arr[10].",
//     options: [
//       "int arr[10]",
//       "arr{10}",
//       "int arr",
//       "arr[10]"
//     ]
//   },
//   {
//     id: 6,
//     question: " Which of the following is â€œaddress of operator?",
//     answer: "&",
//     options: [
//       "%",
//       "&",
//       "*",
//       "&&"
//     ]
//   },
//   {
//     id: 7,
//     question: ". Identify the correct example for a pre-increment operator.?",
//     answer: "++n",
//     options: [
//       "--n",
//       "n++",
//       "+n",
//       "++n"
//     ]
//   },
//   {
//     id: 8,
//     question: "Using which of the following data type can 19.54 be represented?",
//     answer: "double.", 
//     options: [
//       "int",
//       "float",
//       "double.",
//       "void"
//     ]
//   },
//   {
//     id: 9,
//     question: "Identify the correct function from which the execution of C++ program starts?",
//     answer: "main()",
//     options: [
//       "start()",
//       "pow()",
//       "new()",
//       "main()"
//     ]
//   },
//   {
//     id: 10,
//     question: "The constants in C++ are also known as?",
//     answer: "literals",
//     options: [
//       "literals",
//       "preprocessor",
//       "const",
//       "none"
//     ]
//   },
//   {
//     id: 11,
//     question: "Which of the following is not a type of constructor?",
//     answer: "Friend constructor",
//     options: [
//       "Copy constructor",
//       "Friend constructor",
//       "Default constructor",
//       "Parameterized constructor"
//     ]
//   },
//   {
//     id: 12,
//     question: "Which of the following is not the member of class?",
//     answer: "Friend function",
//     options: [
//       "Static function",
//       "Friend function",
//       "Const function",
//       "Virtual function"
//     ]
//   },
//   {
//     id: 13,
//     question: "How many instances of an abstract class can be created?",
//     answer: "0",
//     options: [
//       "1",
//       "5",
//       "13",
//       "0"
//     ]
//   },
//   {
//     id: 14,
//     question: "Which of the following cannot be friend?",
//     answer: "Object",
//     options: [
//       "Function",
//       "Class",
//       "Object",
//       "Operator function"
//     ]
//   }
// ];

let questions = [
  {
    "id": 1,
    "question": "Who invented Java?",
    "answer": "James Gosling.",
    "options": [
      "Dennis Ritchie",
      "Ken Thompson",
      "James Gosling",
      "Bjarne Stroustrup"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": 2,
    "question": "Which keyword is used to define a constant in Java?",
    "answer": "final",
    "options": [
      "static",
      "final",
      "const",
      "constant"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": 3,
    "question": "Which of the following is the correct way to declare an array in Java?",
    "answer": "int[] array;",
    "options": [
      "array int[];",
      "array[] int;",
      "int array[];",
      "int[] array;"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": 4,
    "question": "What is the output of the code snippet: System.out.println(10/3); ?",
    "answer": "3",
    "options": [
      "3.333",
      "3.0",
      "3",
      "3.3333333333333335"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": 5,
    "question": "What is the entry point method in a Java program?",
    "answer": "public static void main(String[] args)",
    "options": [
      "public static void start(String[] args)",
      "public void main(String[] args)",
      "public static void run(String[] args)",
      "public static void main(String args)"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": 6,
    "question": "Which of the following operators is used to compare whether two objects are equal in Java?",
    "answer": "==",
    "options": [
      "==",
      "=",
      "!=",
      ".equals()"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": 7,
    "question": "What is the correct syntax for a single-line comment in Java?",
    "answer": "//",
    "options": [
      "/*",
      "//",
      "*/",
      "#"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": 8,
    "question": "Which of the following is a valid declaration of a String in Java?",
    "answer": "String str = \"Hello\";",
    "options": [
      "String str = Hello;",
      "String str = \"Hello\";",
      "str = Hello;",
      "str = \"Hello\";"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": 9,
    "question": "What is the output of the code snippet: System.out.println(\"Java\".length()); ?",
    "answer": "4",
    "options": [
      "5",
      "4",
      "6",
      "The program will not compile."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": 10,
    "question": "Which keyword is used to prevent method overriding in Java?",
    "answer": "final",
    "options": [
      "static",
      "const",
      "override",
      "final"
    ]
  }
];

let question_count = 0;
let points = 0;

window.onload = function() {
  show(question_count);

};

function next() {

   
  // if the question is last then redirect to final page
  if (question_count == questions.length - 1) {
    sessionStorage.setItem("time", time);
    clearInterval(mytime);
    location.href = "end.html";
  }
  console.log(question_count);

  let user_answer = document.querySelector("li.option.active").innerHTML;
  // check if the answer is right or wrong
  if (user_answer == questions[question_count].answer) {
    points += 10;
    sessionStorage.setItem("points", points);
  }
  console.log(points);

  question_count++;
  show(question_count);
}

function show(count) {
  let question = document.getElementById("questions");
  let [first, second, third, fourth] = questions[count].options;

  question.innerHTML = `
  <h2>Q${count + 1}. ${questions[count].question}</h2>
   <ul class="option_group">
  <li class="option">${first}</li>
  <li class="option">${second}</li>
  <li class="option">${third}</li>
  <li class="option">${fourth}</li>
</ul> 
  `;
  toggleActive();
}

function toggleActive() {
  let option = document.querySelectorAll("li.option");
  for (let i = 0; i < option.length; i++) {
    option[i].onclick = function() {
      for (let i = 0; i < option.length; i++) {
        if (option[i].classList.contains("active")) {
          option[i].classList.remove("active");
        }
      }
      option[i].classList.add("active");
    };
  }
}
